[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu. Wa salli ala rasulina kareem. Ma ma ba'd. Okay. Previously, we finished the ninth lesson, right? What page did we end off at? Page three, okay, yeah. So we finished lesson number nine. And inshallah, today we'll start lesson number ten. But before we did that, I believe we had a lot of homework, right? No? Who said no? Who said no? Too much. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] So let's see. We start off with page 51, right? For this, all you have to do is translate, I said, right? So let's see. Who wants to go ahead and start? Anybody? Nobody? Go ahead. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Yeah, you should know it well, man. The new doctor is in the hospital, and the old doctor is in the urgent care. Good. Yeah, urgent care. That's what we said, yeah. Good. Urgent care? Yeah, we... I didn't know what a dispensary was. I just assumed it's a place where you get medicine from. But then some of the brothers in the class clarified that dispensary is actually like a smaller clinic. So we basically figured out it's something like an urgent care. So, yeah. First aid. First aid, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, yeah. Okay, next. Good. So again, we're solidifying the concept of mausuf and sifa, right? Or na'at and man'ut, right? Al-qalamu al-maksuru, right? So they both are the same end. They're both definite. They're both singular. They're both male. And they both have dhamma. They're both... Al-qalamu al-maksuru. Al-qalamu al-maksuru. Good. Next. Al-maktabi. Yeah. Yeah. Al-murwah, as we said, was a... Fan, yes. Like that type of fan. Like the one that gives you air. Very good. The new fan is in the big room. Good, mashallah. Next one. For the qabbal, next one.
[SPEAKER_00] Al-lughatun arabi, arabiyatun sahilatun. Yeah, sahilatun. Sahilatun. Good. The Arabic language is easy. Good. The Arabic language is easy. Good. Al-wala, al-wala, al-qawli, al-muladi, al-raja, al-fasal, al-aal, talid, al-aana. Al-aana. Al-aana, talid, al-aana. Talib, is it talibin, taliban, talibun? Which one is it? Talibun, yes. Talibun in Hindi, good. Translate, please. The tall boy. The tall boy is exiting. Who, no. The tall boy, who. Who is exiting. Kharaja is past tense, right? He exited.
[SPEAKER_00] He left. From the class, Al-Hind. Right now, he's a student from Al-Hind. Yes. The tall boy who left right now from the classroom. Al-aana, remember, means right now. Right? Kharaja min al-fasli, who left from the classroom right now, is a student from Al-Hind. So basically, Basically, kharaja min al-fasli, al-aana, right? You pretend like, in terms of the broader picture of the sentence, you pretend like it doesn't exist. It's just there to describe al-walad al-taweel, right? But the actual sub, the predicate of the sentence is, like, let's say if you were to erase all that, it would just be, al-walad al-taweel, talibun min al-Hindi. You get it? That's an easier way to understand it, right? Yeah. Al-ladi, and whatever is contained in that, like I told you, it's called al-sirat al-mawsul, right?
[SPEAKER_00] Whatever is contained in that is just for the purpose of describing al-walad al-taweel, right? So if you can't allow it, it'll be easier for you to figure out what comes after it, right? Kharaja min al-fasli, al-aana, talibun. So basically, what we're saying here, the main idea here is that al-walad al-taweel, talibun min al-Hindi. The tall boy is a student from India. But al-ladi kharaja min al-fasli, al-aana, is just to further describe him with a sentence. Everybody understand that? Yeah. So that's one of the main things we learned last time was al-ladi, right? I think I told you guys to find something from the Qur'an, right? Or no? No? Okay. Or maybe that was a class before I told you guys to find al-qayru al-munsarif from the Qur'an. Anyways, let's continue. Continue? Who's reading next? Rahman? Ana fit madrasati thanawiyati. Athanawiyati. Thanawiyati. I am in secondary school. Yeah, good.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, fine. Yeah, fine. Okay. The poor man went to... I don't know what he did. Was he a minister? Minister? Yeah, minister. Like the poor man went to the minister? Yeah. Could it also be... Yeah, it could also be that. Yeah, you could word it either way. But generally though, you'll see that in Arabic, they put the verb first and then they put the doer of the verb, right? So the verb usually comes first, normally in Arabic. Okay, next. Brother Tawheed. Or actually, who's next? Oh, Brother Jibreel, sorry. Number nine. No, sorry, number eight.
[SPEAKER_00] Number eight? Yeah. What does khalfa do to what comes after it? Khalfa? Yeah. Yes. Khalfa is... What is it? Which family is it part of? Zarf. Zarf, right? And so what does it do? It's mudhaf to what comes after it. So it makes what comes after it kasra. Right? So khalfa haamidin. Okay. Translate it. Now you got it, man. You got it. You remember jalasa? You remember jalasa, right? Jalison. What does jalison mean?
[SPEAKER_00] Jalison means something like a student who is sitting behind a man. Who wants to help them out. Okay. Student who is sitting behind a man... Sorry. No, no. Repeat again. Jalisa thalifu. Jalisa thalifu. Jalisa thalifu. Jalisa thalifu. Student who is sitting behind a man. A man is you. No, because if you were to translate like that, if you were to say it in Arabic, it would be Atalibu alladhi jalasa. سَخَلْفَ حَامِدٍ جَدِيدٌ That's how you would say it according to the way you translate it. But this is, the structure is a little different so it gives a slightly different meaning. Good, good. The new student is sitting behind Hamid. Very good, right? Sitting, yeah, sitting, yeah. The new student is sitting. So جَلَسَ, the doer, the one who is doing the sitting is the طَالِب, the student, right? So you translate it like that. The new student is sitting behind Hamid. Hamid, very good translation. Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, the sentence is جَلَسَ so he sat behind. Oh yeah, sat, yeah, sat, right, yeah. It would be جَلَسَ. He sat behind Hamid. Okay. Next, somebody, who's next? Brother Bukhtar? No, okay, come on. Number nine. أَسَّكِنُ أَسِكِنُ أَسِكِنُ أَسِكِنُ You said كَبِيرٌ أَسِكِنُ كَبِيرٌ كَبِيرٌ Yeah. أَسِكِنُ هَادٌ جِدًا Good. Okay. سُكَان سُكَان سُكَان سُكِنَ سُكِنُ كَبِيرٌ Good, good. No, sorry, not
[SPEAKER_00] the sharp knife. سُكِنُ كَبِيرٌ What does the big mean? I mean, كَبِيرٌ كَبِيرٌ كَبِيرٌ The big knife? Uh-huh. سُكِنُ كَبِيرٌ سُكِنُ كَبِيرٌ حَادٌ حَادٌ we mentioned last time was? شَارْب شَارْب جِدًا جِدًا means? Very. Very. Yeah, so translate it now to get all together. Okay. The big knife is very sharp. Very sharp, yes. Good. The big knife is very sharp. Good. Okay, next. You went already, no? Yeah. So let's... Yeah. Go ahead. من آدَ فَلَدُ السَّوِّرُ Uh-huh. هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ Remember, this is Hamzat al-Wasl, right? هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ الْجَرِّي
[SPEAKER_00] دُرْحَة Wait, hold on. هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ Is it كَسْرَة or فَتْحَة or ضَمَّة? هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ مُدَرِّ Why? Can anybody remind him what this is? مُضَوْفُ اللَّهُ فِي لَيْهِ مُضَوْفُ اللَّهُ فِي لَيْهِ So therefore, what would it be? It would have a... هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ Yes. هُوَبْنُ الْمُدَرِّ سِلْ جَدِي دِي Why? But, you know, why is جَدِيد? Because مُدَرِّ says مُضَوْفُ إِلَي But what does جَدِيد have to do with it? I heard Brother Ali said it, but... Why is جَدِيد also كَسْرَة?
[SPEAKER_00] Because it's مُضَوْفُ صِفَة Yeah, it's مُضَوْفُ صِفَة Because جَدِيد is describing المُدَرِّس Right? And so مُضَوْفُ صِفَة have to be the same in their حَرَكَة And their gender And their singularity And it's being definite Right? So that's why هُوَ ابْنُ الْمُدَرِّسِ الْجَدِيدِ Okay, translate now Who is a small boy He is the son of the new teacher Good He is the son of the new teacher Very good translation Okay, let's go Now, إِمْنَا الْفَرَاخِ So basically you have to fill in the blanks Right? This is very easy Right? All you have to do is To fill in the blanks with that word That's in the parentheses But you have to fill it in as a صِفَة Of the word that's mentioned before it
[SPEAKER_00] Right? So it's pretty simple Pretty straightforward Because since it's الْمُدَرِّسِ So you have to change it جَدِيدٌ To something that matches الْمُدَرِّسِ Right? So now who's going to go first? مُدَثِر Good أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسِ جَدِيدٌ? Good أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ الْجَدِيدُ Because Remember the مُصُوف and صِفَة have to be the same In terms of In terms of their being definite or indefinite Right? So that's why you say أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ الْجَدِيدُ Not أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ جَدِيدٌ That wouldn't make sense Good وَلِي أَلْتَاجِرُ أَلْكَبِيرُ Good فِالسُّوقُ فِالسُّوقَ Or فِالسُّوقِ Which one? فِالسُّوقِ Why?
[SPEAKER_00] You don't know? Come on Who knows? فِي فِي حرف الجار This should be second nature by now The حرف الجار makes the word after it كَسْرَ فِالسُّوقِ Okay أَلْتَاجِرُ الْكَبِيرُ فِالسُّوقِ The big Translate it What's a تاجر? Business man? Yeah The big business man He's not just any business man He's a big He does big business Right? Yeah Yeah So فِالسُّوقِ What means? Anybody else? Quickly We don't have much time In the marketplace In the marketplace سُّوقِ Marketplace Alright Third brother دَاوُود
[SPEAKER_00] Good Over here you don't change anything Why? Because طَالِبٌ is also نَكِرَ It's also indefinite So قَدِيمٌ would have to stay as indefinite to match it Right? Translate Yeah Alright Next Now brother You can go جَاوَرَ جَلَسَ طَالِبُ جَدِيدُ خَلْفَ مُحَمَّدُ So جَدِيدُ Just clarify a little bit more You said جَدِيدُ But you made it neither definite nor indefinite So طالب is definite So جَدِيدُ So it has one chapter So I think جَدِيدُ should be one Yeah But you're missing something though Which one am I missing? You said الطَّالِبُ جَدِيدُ جَدِيدُ جَدِيدُ So what's missing here? So what's missing here? Remember
[SPEAKER_00] something can either Generally speaking Either it's As-tanween If it doesn't have tanween It'll have ال Right? So over here How would you say it? So over here Yeah الْجَدِيدُ الْجَدِيدُ Yeah Yeah Because it has to follow الطَّالِبُ And it's And it's Being definite So you have to be الطَّالِبُ الجَدِيدُ Okay Translate it quickly الْجَدِيدُ الْجَدِيدُ الْجَدِيدُ The new student sat in front of Muhammad خَلْف is behind Yeah behind Muhammad The new student sat behind Muhammad Good Alright حُمِيل من الولد القوين من الولد من الولد من الولد Yeah من الولد الطبيب من الولد الطبيب Continue من الولد القوين الذي خرج الآن من القصر Yeah من الولد
[SPEAKER_00] القوين الذي خرج الآن من القصر الآن الآن Which one? الآن No It's الآن As we learned that الآن Pretty much always it's going to be with the with the Sorry Because it is a Zarf Remember the general rule for Zarf is that it's فتحة because it indicates towards time or place And even in the Quran it comes as الآن Right Okay الآن خفف الله عنكم الآن خفف الله عنكم قالوا الآن جئت بالحق قالوا الآن جئت بالحق قالوا الآن جئت بالحق Yeah He said Yeah He said But so is الولد Why Because it's the The predicate and the subject Right من الولد Who is the boy? Right That's why it's Okay So translate it Who is the tall boy Who just left from the classroom? Yes Good Who is the tall boy Who just left from the classroom?
[SPEAKER_00] Right الآن means just Now So I mean If you want to translate it easily You can just say Just left Good Brother Haqq عمار ولد عمار عمار ولد ولد ولد ولد ولد Goodазыв قصير ولد ولد Wow أسوج أسوج أسوج Velad corden؟ well أسUNG أسوج أسوج أسوج equilibrio الأقين أس معصوف موصوف عمار Baby Waladun means boy Waladun is a son right It could mean son or boy Boy So Ammarun is a small boy Qasir means short Right The difference between Sama'a would be saghir Qasir
[SPEAKER_00] means short Okay Shahirun Good Yeah Because they're both Again Tabib is indefinite So shahirun Should also be indefinite Yeah Translate it Faisal Faisal is a Good doctor Shahir means famous Famous Faisal is famous Faisal is famous Faisal is a famous doctor Okay Good Brother Mustafa Good Yeah Yeah Who does this broken bed belong to Broken bed Good Alright Now Who didn't go yet Brother Shokatanko
[SPEAKER_00] Think this adhan That's mean This box Don't answer This, It means It means That's mean That's mean This is هذا قلم مكسور This is a broken pen Yeah, like that This is a broken pen Right Okay, but the answer أين السكين الحاد Good أين السكين الحاد Good, very good You add أل because السكين has أل So the صفة should also follow it in that And also with
[SPEAKER_00] the three other things Okay, what does that mean? Is this a sharp knife? No, what does أين mean? Oh, where is the sharp knife? Yeah, where is the sharp knife? Good, very good Where is the sharp knife? Very good السكين الحاد Good Well, let's go in order Brother حنظر What was your name? حمزة حمزة No, no I think you're in the beginning of the book Or 53? You're on 53? 53? Are we in the same place? Oh, I didn't even see that SubhanAllah Okay,
[SPEAKER_00] yeah, you're right I didn't even see that one Okay, continue Yeah لمن هادي هاديهس لمن هادي سيارة Good لمن هادي السيارة Fill in the blank Fill in the blank جميلة Yeah الجميلة Because السيارة has ال So جميلة is describing السيارة So it should also be the same in terms of its Having ال or not And also in its gender In its حركة And in its being singular So it should be the same in all four of these things So that's why we say السيارة الجميلة Right? You want to translate it? Okay Brother Rokashi, you want to help him translate it?
[SPEAKER_00] Whose is this beautiful car? Yeah, don't give it nazir But yeah, whose beautiful car is this? Right? Good Okay, now Brother Saqif Yeah أطوالب الذي خوج من الفصل الآن من بوليسيا Yeah The student is the one that left No, no, not is the one The student who left from the classroom just now The school just left from the classroom is from Indonesia Good, it's from Indonesia Again, if you read it like how I explained to you earlier Where الذي And then the sentence that comes after which is describing the طالب For example الذي خرج من الفصل الآن Who left from the classroom right now All of that is describing الطالب So consider that as if it's not there So that you can understand what the sentence is trying to say So basically what the sentence is trying to say is الطالب من
[SPEAKER_00] إندونيسيا Right? الذي خرج الآن من الفصل الآن It's all describing الطالب You get it? So don't get confused That's when you'll say If you get confused with that Then you'll say things like The طالب, the student Is the one who left from the classroom right now But then من إندونيسيا Where would that go? Right? So that's why you have to make it clear That the subject is الطالب And the predicate is من إندونيسيا The student is from Indonesia And everything in between is just describing الطالب So you translate like that The student Who left from the classroom right now Is from Indonesia Yeah, exactly الذي, الذين, التي, التي All those So I translated as student Who now Yeah, no, it's good That's perfect Yeah Good translation Okay, next
[SPEAKER_00] That's wrong, yeah Because if you wanted to say that In Arabic, you would say الطالب الذي من إندونيسيا خرج الآن من الفصل You get it? So the way you order instructor sentence Actually changes the meaning And the understanding What we get from it Okay, Brother Hussain? الكتاب اللذي على المكتب المدرسي The book that's on the table belongs to the teacher Good The book that is on the table Belongs to the teacher So again Pretend as if الذي أن على المكتب That whole part is just to describe كتاب Pretend it doesn't exist And you say الكتاب للمدرس The book belongs to the teacher And then you add in التي على المكتب Which is on the table, right? So then you get The season Yeah, basically You put it like That's a good way to put it, right? But you basically put parentheses on that part Like just to make as if To make you understand That this is like Not
[SPEAKER_00] technically part of the main part of the sentence Right? It's just describing that word Right? Let's just Okay, let's go for the next one Brother Harun Good, okay Whose pen is beautiful No Whose beautiful pen Good Whose beautiful pen Is on the table Okay, but slight mess up in the translation To whom belongs this beautiful pen هذا القلم الجميل هذا القلم الجميل Right? To whom belongs this beautiful pen That is On the desk Right? Again So take التي على المكتب Pretend you put it in parentheses Right? لمن هذا القلم الجميل Over here it's not so hard
[SPEAKER_00] Because التي is all the way at the end So it doesn't really affect The way you translate the sentence Okay, Brother Salim I'm learning some explanation في ذلك الشارع في ذلك الشارع Yeah, because of في Because of في So the في Makes the word After it Because I get it That you're saying In that street It affects the second word After it as well Yeah, that's something A rule that we didn't learn yet Okay But ذلك الشارع They're basically like describing It's like there's one thing basically You consider it as like one thing في ذلك الشارع في ذلك الشارع So it's The big house Which is in that street Belongs to the minister Yeah So again Make الذي في ذلك الشارع As if it's in parentheses Right? So basically what you're saying is البيت البيت البيت الكبير للوزير The big house belongs to the minister But الذي في ذلك الشارع Is just describing البيت الكبير So then
[SPEAKER_00] In the end what you get You get The big house Which is in that street Belongs to The The minister Right? Very good Brother Hamad في غرفة خالد Good Okay Translate it السرير الذي في غرفة خالد مكسور السرير You remember what it is? Car No سيارة Oh chair No You got some wrong وحي From brother Samir Yeah There is a bed Yeah Oh So So Khalid's bed is No where is Khalid? Who's Khalid? Khalid Oh okay No no It's not Khalid?
[SPEAKER_00] I didn't say It's not any of Khalid For the bed The bed has nothing to do with Khalid The bed that is inside Oh The broken The broken The broken Belongs to Khalid Say it again The broken bed Belongs to Khalid No The bed that is inside Khalid's room Is broken Good The bed that is in The Khalid's room Is broken Very good Right Just to emphasize that point Like To put it how brother Hussain mentioned So This time I was looking at this This one specifically Took like five minutes Which one? This one that we were doing Oh okay But the trick that you're telling us to use Works best for this one Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah It's like you can't say As-sareeru Khalid Yeah Okay
[SPEAKER_00] So guys listen Do you guys understand the point That I was saying about Pretending as if Al-ladi And what comes after it Doesn't exist Right I'm just gonna show you here Like brother Hussain was suggesting Maybe you could put that in parentheses And pretend as if it's not part of the sentence So like look As-sareeru This is the subject right The bed Right The bed Now what about the bed So the sentence is just telling us That the bed is broken Okay So the bed Is broken As-sareeru maksoorun Right Now all of this We pretend In terms of Trying to understand What the whole sentence means You pretend this doesn't exist first First you figure out Okay As-sareeru maksoorun The bed is broken But now this sentence Describes sareer more So then you Now you Add it into the equation You say The bed Is broken Which is in The room of Khalid Is broken Everybody understand that Does it make more sense now So hopefully InshaAllah Through this formula We can InshaAllah
[SPEAKER_00] Understand this concept better I honestly forgot English grammar But it's possible Okay So Yeah, it's Khalid Din, right? Because maksoorun is describing It's the predicate of as-sareeru You get it? Khalid Din is maksoor Why is it maksoor, anybody? Why is Khalid maksoor? Why is it? Why does it have kasra? Sorry, I confused you guys Because The word that has kasra Is called maksoor in Arabic But I didn't want to I never told you guys that term Because it's confusing So I know You guys are probably Really confused with that Why does Khalid have kasra? No It's mudaf ilay To Ghurfa
[SPEAKER_00] The room of Khalid Right So ghurfati Khalidin Maksorun Okay Everybody understand that? Wait, so what's As-sareeru Would that be Mugtada Sorry What's as-sareeru Be Mugtada And maksoorun Yeah, exactly As-sareer is the Subject of Mugtada And this is the khabar The predicate Right So that's what I'm saying That's why this This parenthesis method Helps you to To separate Okay That's not That's not part of the main part Of the sentence It's just describing The sadeer You get it? So hopefully InshaAllah everybody should Get this concept Of alladi And how We understand it In the sentence Everybody got it? Okay I have a question Yeah, sure Let's go back to number four I just want to understand Maybe it's a technical thing I just I had a hard time Translating this So The way we say The big house is Is on the street Not in the street Right? Shouldn't be On the street Instead of Should be I mean That's how we speak In English Right?
[SPEAKER_00] In English We say it's On the street Right? But in other languages For example I don't know In Urdu How do we say How would we say In Urdu? Like it's on Such and such street The house is on Such and such street You say Uski upar hai? Par Par, okay Yeah But maybe in other languages They say it in different ways So in Arabic You say fi It's in that street It's just It's just a matter of The way you say it In different languages You're right Because if you have an accident You're like Get out the street Yeah Get out Because you're in the street That's a good point Yeah Good point, yeah Yeah, but you're on the street So get off the street Yeah, okay Impossible So yeah Yeah, but in Arabic You say fi Yeah But I think I mean In colloquial Arabic Like in In spoken Arabic I think people
[SPEAKER_00] Probably say Alaa too Alaa shari Yeah, yeah Yeah, sometimes We just have to understand That in Arabic You know They have certain Ways of saying things That we might not do So Yeah In the street Yeah Yes Yeah Yeah, that's true Yeah That's why you say No matter how you look at it Once somebody Trans Like translate You might get the form Yeah, exactly Exactly Yeah Exactly That's why we're learning Arabic itself So we don't have to go through That second step of translating Yeah Exactly, yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah I don't think We can get to the next lesson With this question But can you explain The noon coming in Like Like It still doesn't make sense We were discussing After class last
[SPEAKER_00] week Okay It confused a bunch of us Alright So Last time we talked about Which sentence Did it come up in? What is the question? وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ Page 50 Look at the second last line On page 50 We went over this last lesson But some brothers Wanted me to re-explain it So I'll explain it again وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ الَّذِي خَرَجَ الْآنَى مِنِ الفَصْلِ Right? Okay, it's already here I don't have to write it again Right? So So وَمَن So Before We do this Pretend this doesn't exist Right? Let's take this out Let me just rewrite it Okay, so وَمَن So before it was supposed to be It's supposed to be like this وَمَن الْوَلَدُ Not الْوَلَدُ
[SPEAKER_00] Because this is حَمْدَةُ الْوَصْلِ That's the key thing to remember here This is حَمْدَةُ الْوَصْلِ So you cannot pronounce it here Because It is in the middle of a sentence Right? So therefore This is سَكِن And this is سَكِن And this is سَكِن too Right? So in Arabic You cannot have Multiple seconds Or two seconds Meaning two Things that don't have Any حَرَكَة on it Together Right? This is called in Arabic الْتِقَاءُ السَّكِنَيْنِ The meaning of two seconds Right? This is not Permissible in Arabic It's not possible For you to even say it How would you even say it? وَمَن Like there's no way To transfer from one letter To the next one Right? So That's why And again As I mentioned Arabs they Especially in the past They They Gave precedence To flow Right? So that's why In any type of scenario In which there's الْتِقَاءُ السَّكِنَيْنِ Where two seconds Meet Here And here Right? They
[SPEAKER_00] Turn the first one Into a كَسْرَ Right? Right? وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ Yeah Although Yeah I won't get into that I don't want to confuse you guys Just forget that So yeah So generally speaking That's how it is For example نَعْقُلْهُ وَاللَّهُ أَحَدٌ Right? So that's تَنْوِين That's what's confusing us Yeah So It'll help Yeah I knew that was Going to come to your mind So Think of it like this So أَحَدٌ So we're writing تَنْوِين Like this Right? Just to make it easier for us But technically speaking What a تَنْوِين Really is Is this أَحَدٌ If you think about it Right? That's literally What you're saying تَنْوِين Is basically a نُون With a سَكِن on it They just make it Into this form To make it easier for you You don't have to write A نُون in every place But in reality A تَنْوِين Is a نُون With a سَكِن on it Right? أَحَدٌ And then it says أَللَّهُ الصَّمَد Right?
[SPEAKER_00] صَمَد Right? So Over here Now you have Again حَمَّةُ الْوَصَل And then This also is The first One is a سَكِن And then The second one is What has a فَتْح On it Right? So again You have Two سَكِن Which are meeting Therefore this turned Into a كَسْرَ أَحَدٌ إِلَّهُ الصَّمَد Everybody understand that? Right? Again There's many examples Of the Quran But I don't know why Again It's not coming to my mind Oh yeah وَيْلُ لِكُلِّ هُمَزَةٍ لُمَزَةٍ إِلَّذِي Right? If you want to continue The ayah You don't say لُمَزَةٍ أَلَّذِي You say لُمَزَةٍ إِلَّذِي Right? And وَنَادَى نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ Yeah We mentioned that last time too وَنَادَى نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ Right? Let's put that here
[SPEAKER_00] So نُوحُن نُوحُن إِبْنَهُ Right? So this has So this is In reality This is actually نُوحُن حُن إِبْنَهُ Right? So now to make it flow You take out this And you make it into this نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ Understand that? Everybody understand that? Yeah Yeah Good عَنِ النَّبَءِ الْعَظِيمِ Right? عَن عَن It's just عَن With a second here Right? عَن النَّبَء Right? Good example Mashallah Right? عَمَّ يَتَسَأَلُونَ عَنِّن Why do you say عَنِّن Right? It's supposed to be عَن النَّبَء Right? But because this is حَمَلَةُ الْوَاصُل And this is also A تَنْوِين Sorry A سَاكِن Right? So this turns into A كَسْرَ So you say عَنِّن نَّبَءِ الْعَظِيمِ
[SPEAKER_00] Everybody understand that now? Yeah Yeah? Okay So we were supposed to Start the next lesson But I think it was good We did this And hopefully The concept of الَّذِي Got solidified Inshallah And the مَصُوصِفَ Got solidified Next lesson Will be the last lesson Before Ramadan Right? Just to again Confirm What we said about Ramadan Did we say that We didn't want to have Extra lessons in Ramadan Because people are busy And so we'll just have Like review or I'm thinking instead of review Because how much review Are we going to do? Right? We pretty much review Every class Right? So maybe we could just I could do something Remember I was saying I wanted to start maybe Another book أَصَصُنَّبِيِّن Like as a On an extra basis Where we can start Practicing whatever All these rules That we're learning Now we can practically Implement all these rules Right? So maybe we could do that Yeah the problem is What time you're going to get Because I work on Saturday
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah so like we said It's going to be optional So even if you don't show up I mean Like that's You know It's okay Obviously it'll be beneficial But you know It'll be recorded So you can take Inshallah Repart Through the recordings So Saturdays were good Or what days? Saturdays And what did I think we decided I think we said After Fajr didn't work I think we said After Fajr doesn't work Because Every Saturday And Sunday over here Inshallah There will be a guest speaker After Fajr So it wouldn't really work Because I expect To expect people To stay even after The guest speaker After Ishrat would be pretty late Right? So I think I'm thinking after Zohar Asr? Before Asr?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah I think after Zohar Is okay Inshallah Saturdays after Zohar I'll Inshallah Think of what We're going to do Inshallah Okay so one thing That's going to be introduced In the next lesson Guys pay attention please Shhh Pay attention One thing that's going to be Introduced in this upcoming lesson Yeah it is Different forms of the verb Past tense verb now Right? So far we only learned one thing Which is Zahaba Kharaja Right? Jalasa But they're all past tense Singular Male And third person Right? Now We're bringing in different forms In this lesson So I think now It might be time To bring the whole thing back To the whole chart For you guys Right? Which is To learn The different conjugations Of Zahaba For example Zahaba Is for singular Male Third person Then Zahaba Is for dual Then Zahabu With a wa at the end Is Three
[SPEAKER_00] or more Right? For For plural Right? They went Right? Zahabat Means she went Singular Zahabata Means both of them Female They went Right? Zahabna Means they went Plural female Right? Zahabta Zahabtuma Zahabtum You went Sorry? Yeah So I think What I'm gonna do Is I'm gonna print out that chart Inshallah Or maybe I'll write it out For you guys I can write it out now too But it's kind of late I mean I think I'm sure brothers want to go Huh? Yeah So eventually You gotta memorize it I think it would be good To leave you off with this As a last lesson Because This actually Almost It's a game changer When it comes to understanding Like Your understanding of the Quran Will like You know Increase significantly Just after Figuring this out Understanding how this works And inshallah then Zahabi Zahabi Zahabi Left Zahabtu
[SPEAKER_00] Zahabtu Means I I left Right? For example It's a family of Mixed male and female How would you say it? Zahabtu Yeah If it's If it's multiple people Usually they just Go by the male They just say Zahabu Right? Zahabti Zahabti means You went You're talking to a female Zahabti You went as a female Yeah Is this also Followed the same line As parada Parada Parada Yeah It's the same thing But it just It just depends on what What verb What root letters You put in that Sequence Yeah sure, I think you're right Al-an You would just put it After, like
[SPEAKER_00] I mean it depends Like what you're saying, right? For example If somebody asks you When do you want to go You just say Al-ana Right? Otherwise you put it Next to the verb Right? For example Yeah When he did that Like you're You're talking about he did it now, right? Usually, yeah. It's not necessary, but usually that's how it's done. Again, you'll get a feeling for it more. Once you read more and more Arabic, you listen to Arabic, you'll get an idea of how to structure sentences more. Bin? It means I'm a student in the university. Not always, but in this context, yeah. All right, inshallah, we can end here.